<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[The Art of Joy]]></title>
  <link href="http://artofjoy.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://artofjoy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-11-02T21:42:41-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://artofjoy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Art of Joy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Embracing Sadness]]></title>
    <link href="http://artofjoy.github.io/blog/2016/11/02/embracing-sadness/"/>
    <updated>2016-11-02T20:36:41-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://artofjoy.github.io/blog/2016/11/02/embracing-sadness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Life is not always filled with moments of joy and happiness, for we face moments of sadness and grief as well. To deny and suppress those feelings because they &ldquo;do not feel good&rdquo; is not wise. Instead, let us feel and express our grief. Let us linger in sorrow for as long as we need to. Let us cry, lament, scream, shout. Whatever we do, let&rsquo;s remember to never ignore the feeling of sadness.</p>

<p>Sadness is a very powerful feeling. Scientifically, it is a feeling that actually has some benefits. Studies have shown that people who were in a sad mood had better memory and judgment and had better EQ in general. Furthermore, those who experienced sadness were more generous and empathetic.</p>

<p>Sadness does in fact seem to be an integral part of our lives, and ironically, in order for us to achieve true joy with self and others, we must learn to embrace sadness. It is an element people turn to in art, music, and literature. It helps us reach out to others for support, and ultimately it brings us closer to each other.</p>

<p><strong>So let&rsquo;s stop separating sadness from joy; rather, let&rsquo;s begin to realize that these two emotions are deeply intertwined with each other, for without grief, there is no love, and without love, there is no grief.</strong> Let&rsquo;s use sorrow or grief to remind us that we can love, to empower ourselves, to convert this energy into enthusiasm and purposefulness, and to use it as motivation to change the world for the better.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
